## Charles Fries

Software Developer

4329 Surita Street Sacramento, CA 95864

T: +1 (916) 801-9352

charliefries@icloud.com http://charlesfri.es

Profile

Incredibly passionate, committed, and consistent software developer, with a great attitude and productive mindset. More than four years of experience working individually on projects or with teams, designing, publishing, and maintaining applications for macOS, iOS, Windows, the Web, using technologies like Swift, PHP, Java, and more. Absolutely proficient in developing full application systems using web APIs, databases, backend processing, file management (S3), and network security (primarily Unix).

Experience

CTO, Shiftcode Inc. - San Luis Obispo, CA - 2017 to Present

- Coordinate technology, development, and customer outreach for a small software consultation business called Shiftcode Inc. (<a href="https://shiftco.de">https://shiftco.de</a>); develop new and maintain existing full stack software systems primarily for iOS, Android, and the web.
- Standard server-side software stack comprises of Ubuntu, NGINX, PHP 7, and MySQL; client-side stack comprises of Swift for iOS, Java or nonnative JavaScript for Android, and PHP/HTML/CSS/JS for frontend websites.
- Contracts include Crytq (private social network for business reviews), Arkitu (farmers market venue locator), TextHippo (mass SMS communication manager for businesses), and others.

Full Stack Software Developer, Freelance - Sacramento, CA - 2013 to 2017

- Developer of EyeMusic, an application that helps individuals with sight impairments navigate through their music, audiobooks, or podcasts on iOS devices.
- Proprietor of Alphex, a currently inactive cryptocurrency trading platform (PHP) and order matching engine (Python) for Bitcoin, Monero, Litecoin, and over a dozen other alternative crytpocurrencies.

Cashier, Emigh Hardware Company - Sacramento, CA - 2013 to 2014

- Held a part-time job during high school at a local family-owned hardware store. Maintained the merit of being the store's youngest employee while there.
- Responsibilities include cashiering and assisting customers find the correct parts and tools for their projects.

Education

Cuesta College – San Luis Obispo, CA – 2015 to Present University of Washington – Seattle, WA – 2014 to 2015 Jesuit High School – Sacramento, CA – 2010 to 2014

Skills

Languages: Swift 4, PHP 7, Java, Objective-C, C++, SQL, HTML/CSS/JS

Applications: Git, Xcode, SSH, NGINX, MySQL, Qt SDK, FTP/SFTP, Microsoft Office

Systems: Ubuntu, iOS, macOS, Android, Debian, Windows

Hardware: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, system administration (AWS, Vultr, home builds)

References

https://github.com/charlesfries

https://www.linkedin.com/in/charlesfries

Please contact for personal and/or additional references